<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="qualimap_logo_cut_small.png" type="QuickForm">
    <name>QualiMap BAMQC</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Qualimap 2 for quality control of alignment data from Whole-genome or Whole-exome sequencing.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro><p>QualiMap BAM QC</p>
		<p>
			<a href="http://qualimap.bioinfo.cipf.es/doc_html/analysis.html#bam-qc">Web Documentation for QualiMapBAMQC</a>
		</p>

        </intro>
        
		<option name="paint_Climits">Paint chromosome limits inside charts.</option>
		<option name="species_comp">Species to compare with genome GC distribution.</option>
		<option name="minhomo_size">Minimum size for a homopolymer to be considered in indel analysis.</option>
		<option name="collect_overlap_pairs">Activate this option to collect statistics of overlapping paired-end reads.</option>
		<option name="chunk_size">Number of reads analyzed in a chunk.</option>
		<option name="threads">Number of threads.</option>
		<option name="windows">Number of windows.</option>
		<option name="outside_stats">Report information for the regions outside those defined by feature-file  (ignored when -gff option is not set).</option>
		<option name="sequencing_protocol">Sequencing library protocol.</option>
		<option name="skip_duplicated">Skip duplicated alignments from the analysis. If the duplicates are not flagged in the BAM file, then they will be detected by Qualimap and can be selected for skipping.</option>
		<option name="sdmode">Specific type of duplicated alignments to skip: only flagged duplicates (0), only estimated by Qualimap (1), both flagged and estimated (2)</option>
		<option name="java_mem_size">Set Java memory heap size e.g. 4G for a very large bam file.</option>

    </fullDescription>
	  
    <ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="bam_file [bam]">Input mapping file in BAM format (sorted by position). [bam]</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="gff_file [gff,gtf,bed]">Feature file with regions of interest in GFF/GTF or BED format. [gff,gtf,bed,opt.]</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="outdir [*]">Output folder for HTML report and raw data. [*]</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="coverage_file [tsv]">File to save per base non-zero coverage. [tsv]</outPort>
	</ports>
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="QualiMapBAMQC Std Output">The text sent to standard out during the execution of QualiMapBAMQC.</view>
        <view index="1" name="QualiMapBAMQC Error Output">The text sent to standard error during the execution of QualiMapBAMQC. (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)</view>
    </views>    
</knimeNode>

