<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="SPAdes.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>SPAdes</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        St. Petersburg genome assembler
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        SPAdes – St. Petersburg genome assembler – is an assembly toolkit containing various assembly pipelines. The current version of SPAdes works with Illumina or IonTorrent reads and is capable of providing hybrid assemblies using PacBio, Oxford Nanopore and Sanger reads.
		<p>
			<a href="http://cab.spbu.ru/files/release3.11.1/manual.html">Web Documentation for SPAdes</a>
		</p>

        </intro>
        
		<option name="paired_read_or">Orientation of reads for paired-end library, the default orientation for paired-end libraries is forward-reverse.</option>
		<option name="mate_pair_or">Orientation of reads for mate-pair library, the default orientation for mate-pair libraries is reverse-forward.</option>
		<option name="single_cell">This flag is required for MDA (single-cell) data. </option>
		<option name="meta">This flag is recommended when assembling metagenomic data sets (runs metaSPAdes).</option>
		<option name="plasmid">This flag is required when assembling only plasmids from WGS data sets (runs plasmidSPAdes).</option>
		<option name="rna">This flag should be used when assembling RNA-Seq data sets (runs rnaSPAdes).</option>
		<option name="iontorrent">This flag is required when assembling IonTorrent data. Allows BAM files as input.</option>
		<option name="version">Prints SPAdes version.</option>
		<option name="only_ec">Performs read error correction only.</option>
		<option name="only_assembly">Runs assembly module only.</option>
		<option name="no_gzip">Forces read error correction module not to compress the corrected reads. If this options is not set, corrected reads will be in *.fastq.gz format.</option>
		<option name="careful">Tries to reduce the number of mismatches and short indels. Also runs MismatchCorrector, a post processing tool, which uses BWA tool. This option is recommended only for assembly of small genomes.</option>
		<option name="threads">Number of threads</option>
		<option name="memory">Set memory limit in Gb. SPAdes terminates if it reaches this limit.</option>
		<option name="kmers">Comma-separated list of k-mer sizes to be used (all values must be odd, less than 128 and listed in ascending order).</option>
		<option name="cov_cutoff">Read coverage cutoff value. Must be a positive float value, or 'auto', or 'off'. Default value is 'off'. When set to 'auto' SPAdes automatically computes coverage threshold using conservative strategy.</option>
		<option name="phred_offset">Alignment match score.</option>

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="paired_read_lib [fastq,fq]">File with interlaced reads for paired-read library [fastq,fq]</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="paired_read_lib_unpaired [fastq,fq]">File with interlaced reads with unpaired reads from paired-end library [fastq,fq]</inPort>
		<inPort index="2" name="mate_pair_lib [fastq,fq]">File with interlaced reads for mate-pair library [fastq,fq]</inPort>
		<inPort index="3" name="single_read_lib [fastq,fq,bam]">File for single-read library [fastq,fq,bam]</inPort>
		<inPort index="4" name="pacbio [fastq,fq]"> File with PacBio CLR reads for hybrid assembly [fastq,fq]</inPort>
		<inPort index="5" name="nanopore [fastq,fq]">File with Oxford Nanopore reads for hybrid assembly [fastq,fq]</inPort>
		<inPort index="6" name="sanger [fastq,fq]">File with Sanger reads for hybrid assembly [fastq,fq]</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="output">Assembly results.[*]</outPort>
 </ports>
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="SPAdes Std Output">The text sent to standard out during the execution of SPAdes.</view>
        <view index="1" name="SPAdes Error Output">The text sent to standard error during the execution of SPAdes. (If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously failing run which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)</view>
    </views>    
</knimeNode>
